A Guide to the Commonwealth Fund records, James Picker Foundation, SG 1, Series 35 FA309
Rockefeller Archive Center
Commonwealth Fund records, James Picker Foundation, SG 1, Series 35
1968-1988
Rockefeller Archive Center
Commonwealth Fund
FA309
10.57 Cubic Feet
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Commonwealth Fund collection was donated to the RAC in 1985. Records in this series were transferred to the RAC by Commonwealth Fund in 1986, as a portion of Accession 1986:069.
Scope and Contents
Contains documentation of annual meetings, board of directors and special meetings, grants, fellowships, scholarships, sabbaticals, accepted and rejected proposals, finacial reports and correspondence.
Arrangement
Arrangement - As received.
Other Finding Aids
Other available finding aids describing the Commonwealth Fund records include:
FA247 Commonwealth Fund Harkness House drawings
FA276 Commonwealth Fund records, Annual Reports, SG 1, Series 4
FA277 Commonwealth Fund records, Archives/Library, SG 1, Series 5
FA278 Commonwealth Fund records, Austrian Program, SG 1, Series 6
FA279 Commonwealth Fund records, Board of Directors, SG 1, Series 7
FA280 Commonwealth Fund records, Capital Grants, SG 1, Series 8
FA281 Commonwealth Fund records, Child Health Demonstrations, SG 1, Series 9
FA282 Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Community Clinics, SG 1, Series 10
FA283 Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Health Studies, SG 1, Series 11
FA284 Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Public Health, SG 1, Series 12
FA285 Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Publications, SG 1, Series 13
FA286 Commonwealth Fund records, Division of Rural Hospitals, SG 1, Series 14
FA287 Commonwealth Fund records, Educational Research, SG 1, Series 15
FA288 Commonwealth Fund records, English Mental Hygiene Program, SG 1, Series 16
FA289 Commonwealth Fund records, Finance Committee, SG 1, Series 17
FA290 Commonwealth Fund records, Grants, SG 1, Series 18
FA291 Commonwealth Fund records, Harkness Family, SG 1, Series 19
FA292 Commonwealth Fund records, Harkness Fellowships, SG 1, Series 20
FA428 Commonwealth Fund records, Harkness Fellowships, Fellows Reports, SG 1, Series 20A
FA293 Commonwealth Fund records, Institute for Child Guidance, SG 1, Series 21
FA294 Commonwealth Fund records, Interface Program, SG 1, Series 22
FA295 Commonwealth Fund records, Legal Research Program, SG 1, Series 23
FA296 Commonwealth Fund records, Living at Home Program, SG 1, Series 24
FA297 Commonwealth Fund records, Mental Hygiene Program, SG 1, Series 25
FA298 Commonwealth Fund records, Miscellaneous - unprocessed
FA300 Commonwealth Fund records, Pilgrim Trust, SG 1, Series 28
FA301 Commonwealth Fund records, Program for the Prevention of Delinquency, SG 1, Series 29
FA302 Commonwealth Fund records, Reference Files, SG 1, Series 30
FA303 Commonwealth Fund records, Reports of the General Director, SG 1, Series 31
FA304 Commonwealth Fund records, Treasurer, SG 1, Series 32
FA305 Commonwealth Fund records, Turndown Lists, SG 1, Series 33 - unprocessed
FA306 Commonwealth Fund records, Vertical File (R. Fitz), SG 1, Series 34 - unprocessed
FA307 Commonwealth Fund records, Visual Materials, SG 1, Series 35
FA389 Commonwealth Fund records, Administration - Historical Files, SG 1, Series 1
FA390 Commonwealth Fund records, Administration - Officers Files, SG 1, Series 2
FA429 Commonwealth Fund records, President, Margaret E. Mahoney, SG 2, Series 1
FA430 Commonwealth Fund records, Book Program, SG 2, Series 2
Conditions Governing Access
Open for researchd. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
File Plan
Former Classification: IX; IV 4B 4
- Commonwealth Fund records, James Picker Foundation, 1968-1988; 35
  - Financial Reports, 1975-1979 (Box 1, Folder 1-4)
  - Financial Reports, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Deferred Proposals, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Exploratory Proposals, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Out of Scope Proposals, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 8-9)
  - Rejected Proposals, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Rejected Proposals - A-Z, 1985 Fall (Box 3, Folder 11-12)
  - Rejected Proposals - A-M, 1985 Spring (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Rejected Proposals - A-M, 1985 Spring (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Rejected Proposals - N-Z, 1985 Spring (Box 4, Folder 16-17)
  - Rejected Proposals - A-M, 1984 Fall (Box 4, Folder 18-19)
  - Rejected Proposals - A-M, 1984 Fall (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Rejected Proposals - N-Z, 1984 Fall (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Program on the Human Qualities of Medicine - Renee Fox Grant 1983, 1983-1984 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Program on the Human Qualities of Medicine - Renee Fox Grant 1982 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Program on the Human Qualities of Medicine - Renee Fox Grant 1981, 1980-1981 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Program on the Human Qualities of Medicine - Renee Fox Grant 1981 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Program on the Human Qualities of Medicine - Renee Fox Grant 1980, 1979-1980 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - International Society of Radiology, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Formation of Radiology Foundation, 1984-1984 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Board of Directors Correspondence, 1978-1983 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Council on Foundations Correspondence, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - General Correspondence, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - General Correspondence, 1976-1979; 1981-1985 (Box 7, Folder 32-36)
  - Annual Meeting, Florida, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Annual Meeting, Key Biscayne, Florida, 1975 March (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Annual Meeting, Key Biscayne, San Francisco, CA, 1978 March (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Presentations to the Board, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Annual Meeting, New York, 1980 April (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Annual Meeting, New York, 1980 October (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - Annual Meeting, Key Largo, Florida, 1981 April (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Annual Meeting, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - Annual Meeting, 1983 March (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - Annual Meeting, 1983 March (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - Annual Meeting, 1984 May (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - Annual Meeting. New York City, 1985 March (Box 9, Folder 48)
  - Annual Meeting. New York City (Margaret E. Mahoney Copy), 1985 March (Box 19, Folder 129)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, Key Biscayne, Florida, 1974-1975 (Box 9, Folder 49)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, Dallas, Texas, 1976 January (Box 9, Folder 50)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, Tarrytown, NY, 1978 January (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, Washington, D.C., 1978 May (Box 9, Folder 52)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, Phoenix, AZ, 1979 April (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - Planning Committee Meeting, 1979 October (Box 9, Folder 54)
  - Meeting, New York City, 1973 September (Box 9, Folder 55)
  - Meeting, Washington, D.C., 1973 November (Box 10, Folder 56)
  - Special Meeting, 1975 January (Box 10, Folder 57)
  - Special Meeting, 1977 January (Box 10, Folder 58)
  - Meeting, Key Biscayne, Florida, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 59)
  - Special Meeting, 1979 February (Box 10, Folder 60)
  - Special Meeting, 1981 October (Box 10, Folder 61)
  - Special Meeting, Philadelphia, PA, 1982 October (Box 10, Folder 62)
  - Special Meeting, 1983 October (Box 10, Folder 63)
  - Special Meeting, 1984 September (Box 10, Folder 64)
  - Special Meeting, 1985 Fall (Box 10, Folder 65)
  - Special Meeting, New York City, 1986 January (Box 10, Folder 66)
  - Harvey Picker Correspondence, 1975-1986 (Box 10, Folder 67)
  - Harvey Picker - AUR Gold Medal Award, 1980-1981 (Box 10, Folder 68)
  - Figley Proposal, University of Washington - Seattle, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 69)
  - Everette James Proposal, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 70)
  - Mettler Scholarship, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 71)
  - Tapley - Radiology Chair Endowment, Columbia University, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 72)
  - Special Grants, 1973-1977 (Box 11, Folder 73)
  - James Picker Foundation, 1969-1975 (Box 11, Folder 74-76)
  - Award Period, 1972-1973 (Box 12, Folder 77)
  - Award Period, 1973-1974 (Box 12, Folder 78)
  - Award Period, 1974-1975 (Box 12, Folder 79)
  - Fellowship Program, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 80)
  - Fellowships, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 81)
  - Fellowships, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 82)
  - Pilot Grants, 1973-1974 (Box 12, Folder 83)
  - Pilot Grants, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 84)
  - Pilot Grants, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 85)
  - Pilot Grants, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 86)
  - Pilot Grants, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 87)
  - Pilot Grants, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 88)
  - Pilot Grants - Rejected, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 89-90)
  - Pilot Grants - Rejected, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 91)
  - Pilot Grants - Rejected, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 92)
  - Pilot Study - Grants Survey, 1968-1971 (Box 13, Folder 93)
  - Pilot Grants - Rejected (Out of Scope), 1975 (Box 14, Folder 94)
  - Scholarship Program, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 95)
  - Scholarships, 1973-1974 (Box 14, Folder 96)
  - Scholarships, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 97-98)
  - Scholarships - Applicants, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 99)
  - Scholarships - Rejected, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 100)
  - Scholarships, 1976 (Box 15, Folder 101-102)
  - Scholarships - Rejected, 1976 (Box 15, Folder 103)
  - Scholarships, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 104)
  - Scholarships - Rejected, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 105)
  - Scholarships - Applicants, 1977-1978 (Box 15, Folder 106)
  - Scholarships - Applicants, 1977-1978 (Box 16, Folder 107)
  - Scholarships, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 108)
  - Sabbaticals, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 109)
  - Sabbaticals - Applicants`, 1977-1978 (Box 16, Folder 110)
  - Sabbaticals, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 111)
  - Sabbaticals - Rejected, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 112)
  - Correspondence, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 113-114)
  - Financial Affairs, 1976-1980 (Box 17, Folder 115-120)
  - Financial Affairs, 1981 (Box 18, Folder 121-122)
  - Financial Affairs - Correspondence, 1972-1981 (Box 18, Folder 123)
  - Financial Affairs, 1982-1983 (Box 18, Folder 124-125)
  - Financial Affairs, 1984-1986 (Box 19, Folder 126-128)
  - Picker Foundation Proposal and Correspondence, 1986-1988 (Box 19, Folder 130)
  - Picker Foundation Proposal and Correspondence, 1986-1988 (Box 20, Folder 131)
  - Commonwealth Fund Correspondence with Picker Foundation, 1986-1988 (Box 20, Folder 132-134)
  - Longitudinal Introduction to Clinical Medicine, Harvard Community Health Plan, 1986 (Box 20, Folder 135)
  - Longitudinal Introduction to Clinical Medicine, Harvard Community Health Plan, 1986 (Box 21, Folder 136)
  - Notification of Change Letter (Requests for Information 1986) (Box 22, Folder 137)
  - Non-Funded Grants - Spring 1986, 1986 Spring (Box 22, Folder 138)
  - Correspondence and Addresses - Re: Mission Statement, 1984 (Box 22, Folder 139)
  - Active Grant - Paid in Full - Lo.-Univ. or CA-San Francisco (Box 23, Folder 140)
  - Active Grant - Paid in Full - Day-University of Pennsylvania (Box 23, Folder 141)
  - Bickel Grant - Assoc. of American Med. Colleges (Box 23, Folder 142)
  - Buckman Grant - The Foundation Center (Box 23, Folder 143)
  - Cope Grant - MA General Hospital (Box 23, Folder 144)
  - Edwards/Obenshaine Grant - University of New Mexico (Box 23, Folder 145)
  - Fein Grant - Harvard (Box 23, Folder 146)
  - Garrity Grant - University of Kentucky (Box 23, Folder 147)
  - Jones Grant - George Washington University (Box 23, Folder 148)
  - Jonsen Grant - Univ. of Ca at San Francisco (Box 23, Folder 149)
  - Lipkin Grant - New York University Medical Center (Box 23, Folder 150)
  - Resnick Grant - La Jolla VA Medical Center (Box 23, Folder 151)
  - Stewart Grant - University of Western Ontario (Box 23, Folder 152)
  - NCRP Grant, 1979 (Box 23, Folder 153)
  - Sorenson Grant - Medical College of Pennsylvania (Box 23, Folder 154)
  - Stillman Grant - University of MA Medical College (Box 23, Folder 155)
  - Bloom Grant - Montefiore Medical Center (Box 23, Folder 156)
  - Sledge Grant - Yale University (Box 23, Folder 157)
  - International Symposium and Conference on Doctor-Patient Communication, 1986 November-1988 (Box 24, Folder 158)
  - Requests for Information, 1984-1986 (Box 24, Folder 159-161)
  - Rejection Brochures (Box 24, Folder 162)
  - Brochures for Past Programs (Box 24, Folder 163)